<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MoodTool</string>
    <string name="get_started">Get Started</string>
    <string name="swipe_guide">Swipe to learn more about the tools</string>
    <string name="this_app_provide">This app provides a suite of different tools to help you lift your mood</string>
    <string name="welcome_to">Welcome to Moodtools!</string>
    <string name="information">Information</string>
    <string name="information_guide">Read basic depression information, follow a thorough guide, and find helpful resources</string>
    <string name="test">Test</string>
    <string name="test_guide">Take a depression questionnaire to measure your symptom severity</string>
    <string name="videos">Videos</string>
    <string name="videos_guide">Discover helpful videos can improve you mood</string>
    <string name="thought_diary">Thought Diary</string>
    <string name="thought_diary_guide">Challenge and reframe you negative thoughts</string>
    <string name="activities">Activities</string>
    <string name="activities_guide">Perform healthy activities and track your changes in mood</string>
    <string name="safety_plan">Safety Plan</string>
    <string name="safety_plan_guide">Develop a safety plan to cope with suicidal thoughts</string>
    <string name="additional_app">Additional Apps</string>
    <string name="setting">Settings</string>
    <string name="support">Support</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>
    <string name="facebook">Facebook</string>
    <string name="twitter">Twitter</string>
    <string name="other">Other</string>
    <string name="contact_us">Contact us</string>
    <string name="webpage">Webpage</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="send_mail">Send mail</string>
    <string name="about_act_1">MoodTools is a pioneer in the burgeoning field of mobile mental health. Founded in 2014, MoodTools has quickly become the top mobile solution for clinical depression.</string>
    <string name="about_act_2">Our mission is to package evidence-based strategies in an accessible design and bring them to our pocket for free to help you recover from clinical depression.</string>
    <string name="version">Version: 2.1</string>
    <string name="title_activity_drawer">DrawerActivity</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Android Studio</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">android.studio@android.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="test_disclaimer">Disclaimer: This PHQ-9 questionnaire is a self-administered instrument used in primary care settings. This test is NOT diagnostic test. Please consult your physician if you are concerned about your mood.</string>
    <string name="start_test">Start Test</string>
    <string name="history">History</string>
    <string name="reminder">Reminder</string>
    <string name="over_last_2_weeks_how_often_bothered">Over the last 2 weeks, how often have you been bothered by…</string>
    <string name="not_at_all">Not at all</string>
    <string name="undo">Undo</string>
    <string name="several_days">Several days</string>
    <string name="more_than_half_the_days">More than half the days</string>
    <string name="nearly_every_day">Nearly every day</string>
    <string name="your_total_score_was">Your total score was</string>
    <string name="enable_notification">Enable Notification</string>
    <string name="call_suicide_hotline">Call Suicide Hotline</string>
    <string name="online_therapy">Online Therapy</string>
    <string name="find_help">Find Help</string>
    <string name="how_to_sleep_better">How to Sleep Better</string>
    <string name="dealing_ith_suicidal_thoughts">Dealing ith Suicidal Thoughts</string>
    <string name="every_2_weeks">Every 2 Weeks</string>
    <string name="sound">Sound</string>
    <string name="default_rington">Default ringtone</string>
    <string name="frequency">Frequency</string>
    <string name="soothing_sounds">Soothing Sounds</string>
    <string name="ted_talks">TED Talks</string>
    <string name="guided_meditations">Guided Meditations</string>
    <string name="date">Date</string>
    <string name="situation">Situation</string>
    <string name="guide_thought_diary">Press the + button to create a new entry or press the ? button to read the instructions.</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="info">Info</string>
    <string name="resources">Resources</string>
    <string name="guide">Guide</string>
    <string name="what_is_depression">What is Depression?</string>
    <string name="symptoms">Symptoms</string>
    <string name="types">Types</string>
    <string name="causes">Causes</string>
    <string name="treatments">Treatments</string>
    <string name="dialectical_behavior_therapy">Dialectical Behavior Therapy</string>
    <string name="suicide_prevention">Suicide Prevention</string>
    <string name="mindfulness_meditation">Mindfulness Meditation</string>
    <string name="acceptance_and_commitment_therapy">Acceptance and Commitment Therapy</string>
    <string name="cognitive_behavioral_therapy">Cognitive-Behavioral Therapy</string>
    <string name="lifestyle_changes">Lifestyle Changes</string>
    <string name="find_a_therapist">Find a Therapist</string>
    <string name="help_guide">Help Guide</string>
    <string name="depression_information">Depression Information</string>
    <string name="depression_is">
        Everyone feels sad at times, but typically these feelings pass within a couple of days. Clinical depression is a biological condition in which sadness (or apathy) becomes so overwhelming that it interferes with your daily life.\n\n
        When you have depression, it is hard to enjoy life, concentrate, and do daily tasks like you used to. You may feel hopeless, unmotivated, persistently down, or very irritable. However, there is hope! With the help of therapy and medication, millions of people have already overcome their depression, and we want to present this same hope to you.\n\n
        Additionally, this application provides multiple tools to help you lift your mood. If you feel like you may be suffering from depression, be sure to ake the Depression Test to get a general sense of your symptom severity. In the Videos section, you can check out helpful videos or curate your own list of mood-boosters. Challenge your negative thoughts by identifying the cognitive distortions within them in th Thought Diary. Perform engaging activities in the Activities section and measure ow they impact your mood. If you are dealing with suicidal thoughts, create a Safety Plan to help keep you safe.
    </string>
    <string name="click_link_for_more_detail">Click on the links below for more detailed information.</string>
    <string name="link_what_is_depression">
        <a href='http://www.apa.org/helpcenter/understanding-depression.aspx'>http://www.apa.org/helpcenter/understanding-depression.aspx</a>
    </string>
    <string name="symptoms_is">The two primary symptoms of clinical depression is a depressed mood most of the day and a lot of interest in normal activities an relationships, with these symptoms occurring nearly every day for at least 2 weeks. Other symptoms may include:</string>
    <string name="symptoms_cause">
        <li>Fatigue or loss of energy</li>\n
        <li>Feelings of worthlessness or guilt</li>\n
        <li>Impaired concentration, indecisiveness</li>\n
        <li>Insomnia or hypersomnia (excessive sleeping)</li>\n
        <li>Markedly diminished interest or pleasure in almost all activities</li>\n
        <li>Restlessness or feeling slowed down</li>\n
        <li>Recurring thoughts of death or suicide Significant weight loss or gain</li>
    </string>
    <string name="symptoms_various_detail">People who have depression do not all experience the same symptoms. The severity, frequency, duration, and type of symptoms vary from person to person.</string>
    <string name="depressive_disorder_various">While most people simply have Major Depressive Disorder, there are also several other subtypes of depressive disorders.</string>
    <string name="major_depressive_disorder">Major Depressive Disorder</string>
    <string name="major_depressive_is">Typical clinical depression is marked by a depressed mood most of the day and a loss of interest in normal activities and relationship, with symptoms that are nearly everyday for at least 2 weeks. Symptoms include:</string>
    <string name="major_depressive_symptoms">
        <li>Depressed mood</li>\n
        <li>Fatigue or loss of energy almost every day</li>\n
        <li>Feelings of worthlessness or guilt almost every day</li>\n
        <li>Impaired concentration, indecisiveness</li>\n
        <li>Insomnia or hypersomnia (excessive sleeping) almost every day</li>\n
        <li>Markedly diminished interest or pleasure in almost all activities nearly every day</li>\n
        <li>Restlessness or feeling slowed down</li>\n
        <li>Recurring thoughts of death or suicide</li>\n
        <li>Significant weight loss or gain (a change of more than 5% of body weight in a month)</li>
    </string>
    <string name="seasonal_affective_disorder">Seasonal Affective Disorder</string>
    <string name="seasonal_affective_disorder_is">Many people develop depression when the season turns from fall to winter. Seasonal affective disorder affects around 1–2% of the population, and is thought to be caused by diminished exposure to bright light. This disorder is more common in extremely northern or southern areas where there is less sunlight during winter. Symptoms of seasonal affective disorder are similar to those of major depressive disorder nd can often be effectively treated with light therapy.</string>
    <string name="link_seasonal_affective_disorder">
        <a href='http://www.webmd.com/mental-health/tc/seasonal-affective-disorder-sad-topic-overview'>http://www.webmd.com/mental-health/tc/seasonal-affective-disorder-sad-topic-overview</a>
    </string>
    <string name="persistent_depressive_disorder">Persistent Depressive Disorder (Dysthymia)</string>
    <string name="persistent_depressive_detail">Persistent depressive disorder, also referred to as chronic depression or dysthymia, has less severe and fewer symptoms than major depression but the condition often lasts for longer periods of time. People often describe feeling like they\'re functioning at "75% of normal." With persistent depressive disorder, there maybe major depressive mood, and a person who is diagnosed would have had depressive symptoms for at least two years. Those who suffer from persistent depressive disorder can also experience periods of major depression-sometimes called double depression.</string>
    <string name="link_persistent_depressive">
        <a href='http://www.webmd.com/depression/guide/chronic-depression-dysthymia'>http://www.webmd.com/depression/guide/chronic-depression-dysthymia</a>
    </string>
    <string name="bipolar_disorder">Bipolar Disorder (Manic Depression)</string>
    <string name="bipolar_disorder_detail">Bipolar disorder, also called manic depression, is a complex mood disorder that alternates between periods of clinical depression and extreme elation or mania. Abnormal behavior during manic episodes includes:</string>
    <string name="bipolar_disorder_symtoms">
        <li>Increased energy, with hyperactivity and a decreased need for sleep</li>\n
        <li>Sudden jumping from one idea to the next</li>\n
        <li>Rapid and loud speech</li>\n
        <li>Inflated self-image</li>\n
        <li>Increase in goal-directed activity (suddenly more productive than usual at work or school, or sexually)</li>\n
        <li>Poor impulse control, engaging in activities with a high potential for painful consequences (excessive spending, sexual indiscretions, uncharacteristic investments)</li>
    </string>
    <string name="addition_info_bipolar_disorder">In addition, people may become delusional or have other psychotic syptoms during a manic episode.</string>
    <string name="link_bipolar_disorder">
        <a href='http://www.nimh.nih.gov/health/topics/bipolar-disorder/index.shtml'>http://www.nimh.nih.gov/health/topics/bipolar-disorder/index.shtml</a>
    </string>
    <string name="postpartum_depression">Postpartum Depression</string>
    <string name="postpartum_depression_detail">Postpartum depression, now called depression with peripartum onset, affects between 3 and 6 percent of women either during pregnancy or in the weeks following childbirth. Symptoms are similar to what typically happens after during pregnancy or childbirth, such as difficulty sleeping, appetite changes, fatigue, decreased sex drive, and mood swings. However, these are also accompanied by other symptoms of major depression such as depressed mood, feelings of worthlessness, hopelessness, thoughts of death, or thoughts of hurting oneself or one\'s baby.</string>
    <string name="link_postpartum_depression">
        <a href='http://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/postpartum-depression/basics/definition/con-20029130'>http://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/postpartum-depression/basics/definition/con-20029130</a>
    </string>
    <string name="atypical_depression">Atypical Depression</string>
    <string name="atypical_depression_detail">Atypical depression is similar in many ways to other types of depression, except that sufferers temporarily experience improved mood in response to positive events or good news. Other atypical depression symptoms include an increased appetite, significant weight gain, excessive sleep, a heavy feeling in the limbs, and sensitivity to rejection.</string>
    <string name="link_atypical_depression">
        <a href='http://www.webmd.com/depression/guide/atypical-depression'>http://www.webmd.com/depression/guide/atypical-depression</a>
    </string>
    <string name="psychotic_depression">Psychotic Depression</string>
    <string name="psychotic_depression_detail">Psychotic depression occurs when a person has serve depression in addition to some form of psychosis, such as having a distorted break from reality or disturbing false beliefs (delusions), or hearing/seeing distressing things that others cannot hear or see (hallucinations).</string>
    <string name="link_psychotic_depression">
        <a href='http://www.webmd.com/depression/guide/psychotic-depression'>http://www.webmd.com/depression/guide/psychotic-depression</a>
    </string>
    <string name="link_depression_types">
        <a href='http://www.webmd.com/depression/guide/depression-symptoms-and-types'>http://www.webmd.com/depression/guide/depression-symptoms-and-types</a>
    </string>
    <string name="depression_causes">Researchers have learned that depression is caused by a combination of genetics, biological, psychological, and environmental factors. Some types of depression run in families, as some genetic research shows certain genes may make some people more vulnerable to depression. Depression likely occurs in people because of various environmental factors as well. Some caused and risk factors for depression may include:</string>
    <string name="detail_causes">
        <li>Loneliness</li>\n
        <li>Lack of social support</li>\n
        <li>Recent stressful life experiences</li>\n
        <li>Family history of depression</li>\n
        <li>Marital or relationship problems</li>\n
        <li>Financial strain</li>\n
        <li>Early childhood trauma or abuse</li>\n
        <li>Alcohol or drug abuse</li>\n
        <li>Unemployment or underemployment</li>\n
        <li>Health problems or chronic pain</li>\n
        <li>Trauma</li>\n
        <li>Loss of a loved one</li>\n
        <li>Loss in self-identity</li>
    </string>
    <string name="causes_of_depression_not_apparent">Often, the causes of depression are not immediately apparent, but working with a trained professional to understand the cause of your depression can help determine the best type of treatment.</string>
    <string name="link_causes_depression">
        <a href='http://www.webmd.com/depression/guide/causes-depression'>http://www.webmd.com/depression/guide/causes-depression</a>
    </string>
    <string name="treatment_guide">The most effective depression treatment varies from person to person. It is important to talk to your doctor or a mental health professional about the best treatment for you. For some, depression may be caused by an underlying medical condition such as hypothyroidism. For most people, psychotherapy and/or antidepressants are effective methods of treatment. Lifestyle changes are also an important element of recovery. Keep in mind that there are no instant cures, and it might take some time and commitment to recover from depression.</string>
    <string name="psychotherapy">Psychotherapy</string>
    <string name="psychotherapy_treatment">Psychotherapy - or "talk therapy" - is an effective treatment for clinical depression and is often the first form of treatment recommended for depression. During psychotherapy, you talk to a licensed and trained mental health professional who helps you work through depression in various ways. This approach teaches you the skills to deal with your depression and help prevent future occurrences of depression as well. Therapy can be given in a variety of formats including individual to find a therapist that you can connect with and trust. In addition, there are several different approaches to therapy. Cognitive-Behavioral Therapy, Acceptance and Commitment Therapy, and Interpersonal Therapy have all been shown to be effective for treating depression, although effectiveness varies from person to person and other therapeutic approaches may work for you as well.</string>
    <string name="antidepressants">Antidepressants</string>
    <string name="antidepressant_treatment">Antidepressant treatment is also effective for treating clinical depression. It is more effective for severe cases of depression, and is commonly combined with psychotherapy for an even greater effect. There are many classes of antidepressants, such as SSRIs, SNRIs, or tricyclic antidepressants. Keep in mind that all of these drugs have various side effects and do not have an immediate effect, they take some time to work. If one antidepressant doesn\'t work well, you might try another drug of the same class or a different class of depression medicines altogether. Your doctor might also try changing the dosage. In some cases, your doctor might recommend taking more than one medication for your depression.</string>
    <string name="brain_stimulation_treatment">When medication and therapy fail to ease the symptoms of clinical depression, there are still additional effective options. Brian stimulation techniques can be used to treat major depression that has not responded to standard treatments. Electorconvulsive therapy (ECT) is the most well-known and proven type of brian stimulation, deep brain stimulation, vagus nerve stimulation, and magnetic seizure therapy.</string>
    <string name="brain_stimulation">Brain Stimulation</string>
    <string name="link_treatment">
        <a href='http://www.webmd.com/depression/psychotherapy-treat-depression'>http://www.webmd.com/depression/psychotherapy-treat-depression</a>
        <!--<a href='http://www.helpguide.org/mental/medications-depression.htm'>http://www.helpguide.org/mental/medications-depression.htm</a>\n-->
    </string>
    <string name="link_treatment2">
        <a href='http://www.webmd.com/depression/guide/electroconvulsive-therapy'>http://www.webmd.com/depression/guide/electroconvulsive-therapy</a>
    </string>
    <string name="add_custom_activity">+ Add custom activity</string>
    <string name="add_your_own_activities">Add your own activities above or edit existing activities below</string>
    <string name="lifestyle_change_guide">Lifestyle changes are simple and essential elements of recovery. They can be used on their own, in conjunction with other treatments, or to prevent relapse. The following components have all been proven to lower symptoms of depression.</string>
    <string name="sunlight">Sunlight</string>
    <string name="exercise">Exercise</string>
    <string name="nutrition">Nutrition</string>
    <string name="sleep">Sleep</string>
    <string name="social_support">Social Support</string>
    <string name="life_style_transition">Life style transition</string>
    <string name="text_view">TextView</string>
    <string name="image_view">ImageView</string>
    <string name="line">Line</string>
    <string name="lack_sunlight_explain">Lack of sunlight can worsen depression or increase the chances of getting depression. If not given enough light exposure, the body\'s biological rhythm can go out of balance, affecting things such as energy, sleep, appetite, and hormones. Therefore, disrupting these regular body rhythms can be bad for mood and trigger depression.</string>
    <string name="lack_sunlight_explain2">Aim for at least 15 minutes of sunshine a day to keep mood and biological rhythms is sync. For wintertime places with little sun, try getting a <a href='http://amzn.to/2pZ1Pip'>light therapy box</a></string>
    <string name="supportive_relationships"><u>Supportive Relationships</u></string>
    <string name="supportive_relationships_guide">Relationships matter. Humans are social creatures, and people who lack a supportive network have a greater risk of becoming depression. Whether preventing depression, overcoming depression, or simply being a happier person, having quality and trusting relationships is an important element of living. When one is in a depressed state, isolation and loneliness can be all the more harmful.</string>
    <string name="supportive_relationships_contain">
        <li>Although it may seem intimidating or intrusive, approach trusted friends and family, preferably face to face, and discuss one\'s depression. Ask for support or help. Reaching out is not a sign of weakness, nor should it be considered a burden to others.</li>\n\n
        <li>Try to keep us with social interactions and activities even if it feels challenging or uncomfortable.</li>\n\n
        <li>Joining a support group for depression can reduce feelings of loneliness and isolation. Support groups can connect people with others who share similar experiences. One can give and receive advice on how to cope with depression, share stories, and encourage one another in a shared space.</li>
    </string>
    <string name="group_therapy"><u>Group Therapy</u></string>
    <string name="group_therapy_detail">A form of depression treatment known as group therapy may be helpful. Such sessions provide an outlet for depressed persons to share their problems, which in itself a powerful healing tool, as well as a platform for mutual learning from each other\'s experiences. Listening to others\' issues helps put one\'s own problems in perspective too.</string>
    <string name="exercise_guide_1">Regular exercise has been shown to reduce stress, ward off anxiety and feelings of depression, boost self-esteem, and improve sleep. Exercise can change the brain by increasing the activity level of key chemicals such as dopamine and serotonin as well as key growth hormones. These brain chemicals can then increase endorphins and reduce stress, leading to improvements in depression symptoms. Exercise can even be as effective as antidepressants at increasing energy and mood while decreasing feelings of fatigue.</string>
    <string name="exercise_include">
        Moderate physical activity produces risk-free benefits for people with depression or without depression. Some examples of moderate exercise include:\n
        <li>Biking</li>\n
        <li>Dancing</li>\n
        <li>Gardening</li>\n
        <li>Housework, especially sweeping, mopping, or vacuuming</li>\n
        <li>Jogging at a moderate pace</li>\n
        <li>Low-impact aerobics</li>\n
        <li>Playing tennis</li>\n
        <li>Swimming</li>\n
        <li>Walking</li>\n
        <li>Yard work, especially mowing or raking</li>\n
        <li>Yoga</li>
    </string>
    <string name="key_start_exercise">The key is to start small and pick enjoyable activities so that one is more likely to keep up with them. To stay motivated, try exercising with supportive group, close friend, or partner. In doing so one can benefit from both physical activity and social support.</string>
    <string name="exercise_link">http://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/depression/in-depth/depression-and-exercise/art-20046495</string>
    <string name="nutrition_detail">Getting proper nutrition is important for recovering from depression, especially because depression can affect appetite. It has been shown that low levels of the nutrients zinc, Vitamin B6, Vitamin B12, omega-3 fatty acids, and folate can lead to an increased risk of depression. Omega-3 fatty acids, in particular, have been shown to be extremely beneficial in keeping the brain functioning properly and decreasing the risk for depression and other forms of mental illnesses.</string>
    <string name="nutrition_contains">
        In addition, people who are clinically depressed often do not eat a balanced diet. Thus, poor nutrition leads to depressive symptoms and depressive symptoms lead to poorer nutrition, resulting in an unhealthy cycle. Tip for having a healthy and mood-boosting diet includes:\n
        <li>Dietary omega-3 fatty acids. Omega-3 fatty acids are found in fish, nuts, seeds, and leafy vegetables. Try taking omega-3 supplements as well.</li>\n
        <li>B vitamins. Lack of B vitamins such as folic acid and Vitamin B-12 can increase risk for depression. Taking vitamin supplements or eating foods such as citrus fruits, leafy greens, chicken, and eggs will increase B vitamin intake.</li>\n
        <li>Cut down on sugar and refine carbs such as candy and french fries. These "feel good" and "quick fix" foods can often lead to a crash in mood and energy.</li>\n
        <li>Eat balanced meals. Eating well-rounded meals from all the food groups makes for balanced nutrition and can improve health and mood.</li>\n
        <li>Do not skip meals. Skipping meals or going too long between meals can increase irritability or tiredness.</li>
    </string>
    <string name="nutrition_link_1">http://www.webmd.com/depression/guide/diet-recovery</string>
    <string name="nutrition_link_2">http://psychcentral.com/lib/can-nutrition-help-fight-or-ward-off-depression/0003150</string>
    <string name="nutrition_link_3">http://www.foodforthebrain.org/nutrition-solutions/depression/about-depression.aspx</string>
    <string name="nutrition_link_4">http://depression.about.com/od/fishoil/a/Omega-3-Fatty-Acids-For-Depression.htm</string>
    <string name="sleep_detail">
        People with depression commonly experience disturbed sleep patterns, but depression can affect sleep in a variety of ways. Research shows that people with insomnia have a ten times higher risk of developing depression, so it is important to ensure a good night\'s sleep every night. Ensuring the quality and quantity of sleep can not only improve mood and symptoms of depression, but can also help stave off things that can trigger a depressive episode. Some sleep hygiene tips includes:\n
        <li>Manage your exposure to light. The key to better sleep hygiene is managing your exposure to light. Your brain depends on the level of ambient light or darkness to manage your daily rhythms. Before bedtime, limit your exposure to light as much as possible and while sleeping.</li>\n
        <li>Exercise. Make sure to get regular exercise and spend some time outdoors in the sunlight every day. This is a good way to set your biologic clock, and it helps maintain a regular sleep-wake cycle. However, try to exercise at least three hours before bed or else the stress hormones released by exercising might keep you up.</li>\n
        <li>Skip the nap. Avoid afternoon naps, which can lead to nighttime insomnia.</li>\n
        <li>Limit caffeine and alcohol, especially later in the day. Caffeine is a stimulant and can keep you wide awake, while alcohol can disrupt sleep quality. Alcohol before bedtime will interfere with sleep and it may help you fall asleep, but you are less likely to sleep through the night.</li>\n
        <li>Get up if you can't sleep. Don't waste time lying in bed looking at your clock. If you find yourself lying awake, the best thing is to get up and do something relaxing until you feel tired.</li>\n
        <li>Shut off the TV and the phone. Avoid watching television late at night. Most shows in the evening are too stimulating and do not promote good sleep. It's better to read a book or do a relaxing activity in the hours before bed. If you must use your phone, download applications that dim the screen down to very dim levels such as 'Screen Filter.'</li>\n
        <li>Turn your bedroom into a sleep-inducing environment. Use your bedroom primarily for sleep and try your best to make it a quiet, dark, and cool environment.</li>\n
        <li>Establish a soothing pre-sleep routine and keep a consistent sleep schedule. Ease your transition from wake time to sleep time with an hour or so of relaxing activities. Take a bath, read a book, or practice relaxation exercises. In addition, sleeping and waking up at the same time every day will help establish a daily rhythm to your brain.</li>\n
        <li>Practice good sleep hygiene. This includes using your bedroom primarily for sleeping and sticking to a regular sleep schedule. Avoid distractions in your bedroom, like phones, computers, too much light, and too much noise. Make sure your bed is comfortable and that the room temperature is comfortable for sleeping.</li>
    </string>
    <string name="sleep_link">http://healthysleep.med.harvard.edu/healthy/getting/overcoming/tips</string>
    <string name="cognitive_therapy">Cognitive Therapy</string>
    <string name="cognitive_therapy_detail">CBT is a problem-focused and action-oriented therapy where you use logic to analyze and challenge your negative thoughts to improve your mood. It\'s been proven to be effective in reducing symptoms of depression and anxiety and is generally considered the most common therapy for depression.</string>
    <string name="challenge_thoughts">Challenge Thoughts</string>
    <string name="cognitive_distortions">Cognitive Distortions</string>
    <string name="cognitive_detail_1">The basic theory behind CBT is that depression is not an emotional disorder, but rather a disorder caused by thoughts. Distorted negative thinking caused the bad moods that accompany depression. Often, these thoughts are so innate that they are almost \'automatic thoughts\' that occur in your mind without any effort. For example, imagine that your friend turns you down for dinner. You may think to yourself, "She does not want to have dinner with me because she hates me. In fact, nobody likes me." This negative interpretation would elicit a bad mood. Alternatively, you may think, "She has been really busy lately. Just because she is too busy for dinner does not mean that she hates me.\" These different interpretations result in vasty different emotional responses.</string>
    <string name="cognitive_detail_2">Cognitive therapy aims to teach you to almost become your own therapist by challenging your negative thoughts. After you have mastered this skill, whenever you feel depressed, you will be able to identify the negative thought that is causing your negative mood, challenge your thought by identifying the distortions within it, and restructure your thought to improve your mood.</string>
    <string name="cognitive_detail_3">Cognitive-behavioral therapy is usually performed with a therapist that can work with you to teach you these skills and identify/challenge your personal core beliefs over several weeks.</string>
    <string name="cognitive_detail_4">A classic book that explains CBT and how to apply it to your own life is <a href='http://amzn.to/2qY7ycC'>Feeling Good</a> by David Burns.</string>
    <string name="challenge_thoughts_detail_1">The central skill of cognitive therapy is to challenge your negative thoughts that are causing your depressed mood.</string>
    <string name="challenge_thoughts_detail_2">First, you must become aware of your negative thoughts. Recognize that feelings are not facts, but rather the result of your thoughts. These thoughts are often automatic, distorted, but plausible. Typically, you simply accept these thoughts as true. Whenever you are feeling bad, try and remember when your mood changed for the worse and recall what was running through your mind at that moment.</string>
    <string name="challenge_thoughts_detail_3">After identifying the thought, it might help to write it down. Then, challenge it with logic. Often these automatic thoughts are illogical or have flawed assumptions within them. Often, there are cognitive distortions within your thoughts, and a list of common cognitive distortions will be covered in the next section.</string>
    <string name="challenge_thoughts_detail_4">Finally after challenging the thought, write down a more realistic and balanced response.</string>
    <string name="cognitive_distortions_detail">Cognitive distortions consist of irrational logic in our thinking. These distortions typically reinforce negative thinking or emotions. They typically occur automatically and we simply accept them as true. However, if we step back from our negative thoughts, we can analyze them for the presence of cognitive distortions.</string>
    <string name="all_or_nothing"><u>All-or-nothing thinking</u></string>
    <string name="all_or_nothing_detail">Thinking in black or white, thinking in extremes. Using words such as \"always\" or \"never\" to describe yourself or situations.</string>
    <string name="should_must_statements"><u>Should / must statements</u></string>
    <string name="should_must_statements_detail">Thinking that you are obligated to do things; using \"should\" or \"must\" statements.</string>
    <string name="should_must_statements_ex">Ex. I should never feel angry. I should feel very guilty.</string>
    <string name="labeling"><u>Labeling</u></string>
    <string name="labeling_detail">Atributing a person\'s behaviors to his/her character or personality (\"this is who she is all the time\") rather than thinking it\'s temporary or just for one event (\"she just made a mistake\")</string>
    <string name="labeling_ex">Ex. That driver honked at me at the intersection so he must be an angry person in general.</string>
    <string name="all_or_nothing_ex">Ex. No one likes me; I am always a bother to other people; I never win anything.</string>
    <string name="overgeneralization"><u>Overgeneralization</u></string>
    <string name="overgeneralization_detail">Making a very broad conclusion based on one event; taking one situation and expecting the same result to happen in all future situations.</string>
    <string name="overgeneralization_ex">Ex. She cannot meet me for lunch today. This means she isn\'t reliable at all.</string>
    <string name="filtering_out_positive"><u>Filtering out the positive</u></string>
    <string name="filtering_out_positive_detail">Only focusing on the negative aspects of an experience while ignoring the positives. Focusing only on information that confirms what you already believe in.</string>
    <string name="filtering_out_positive_ex">Ex. He didn\'t like the chicken I made for dinner but loved the vegetables and dessert. I feel that my cooking skills are terrible because the chicken was bad.</string>
    <string name="jumping_conclusions"><u>Jumping to conclusions</u></string>
    <string name="jumping_conclusions_detail">Reaching a hasty conclusion or judging something without having enough facts.</string>
    <string name="jumping_conclusions_ex">Ex. She came home with a frown on her face, so she must be angry with me.</string>
    <string name="mind_reading"><u>Mind reading</u></string>
    <string name="mind_reading_detail">Assuming or inferring another person\'s thoughts or expecting for the worst possible scenario without actually confirming with the person or having solid evidence.</string>
    <string name="mind_reading_ex">Ex. My friend did not wave back at me when I waved to her from across the street. She must be angry with me right now.</string>
    <string name="fortune_telling"><u>Fortune-telling</u></string>
    <string name="fortune_telling_detail">Predicting a negative outcome before the event happens</string>
    <string name="fortune_telling_ex">Ex. The boss will definitely not like my presentation; My boyfriend will definitely hate my new haircut.</string>
    <string name="magnification_negative"><u>Magnification of the negative</u></string>
    <string name="magnification_negative_detail">Putting greater emphasis on possible failures, weaknesses, or threats.</string>
    <string name="magnification_negative_ex">Ex. During my class presentation I made a couple of mistakes while talking. My teacher and peers complimented me on a good presentation afterwards, but I continued to feel embarrassed about the things I messed up on.</string>
    <string name="minimization_positive"><u>Minimization of the positive</u></string>
    <string name="minimization_positive_detail">Putting lesser emphasis on possible success, strength or opportunity.</string>
    <string name="minimization_positive_ex">Ex. When someone compliments me, instead of feeling proud of my achievement I discount their compliments as simply being polite.</string>
    <string name="catastrophizing"><u>Catastrophizing</u></string>
    <string name="catastrophizing_detail">Over-exaggerating; believing in the worse case scenario or thinking something is extremely unbearable or impossible when it actually isn\'t that bad.</string>
    <string name="catastrophizing_ex">Ex. I knocked over that glass bottle and I feel mortified that everyone who is staring at me must think that I am a clumsy and useless person.</string>
    <string name="emotional_reasoning"><u>Emotional reasoning</u></string>
    <string name="emotional_reasoning_detail">Believing that if you feel that something is true it must be true.</string>
    <string name="emotional_reasoning_ex">Ex. I feel so dumb and useless, therefore I must be dumb and useless.</string>
    <string name="self_blaming"><u>Self-blaming</u></string>
    <string name="self_blaming_detail">Blaming yourself or thinking you\'re personally responsible for a situation that you actually have little control over.</string>
    <string name="self_blaming_ex">Ex. I was late to work because of a road accident, but I should have known that in advance.</string>
    <string name="other_blaming"><u>Other-blaming</u></string>
    <string name="other_blaming_detail">Blaming others or holding other people responsible for things done to you that they may have little control over.</string>
    <string name="other_blaming_ex">Ex. She should have been more careful when she knocked over that glass bottle.</string>
    <string name="thought_diary_guide_detail">A thought diary is included within this application. The instructions on using it are as follows.</string>
    <string name="thought_diary_do"><u>What does a thought diary do?</u></string>
    <string name="thought_diary_do_detail_1">Do you feel like you\'re stressed, anxious, sad, frustrated, or unmotivated? The centerpiece of cognitive-behavioral therapy is changing your emotions by identifying negative and distorted thinking patterns. Thought Diary aims to help you take a step back from your thoughts and identify negative and distorted thinking patterns.</string>
    <string name="thought_diary_do_detail_2">After completing a thought record, your distress levels should go down. Over repeated use, you will likely find that you will learn to think differently about the situations you find yourself in, significantly increasing your everyday mood. Don\'t be discouraged if you do not feel much better quickly after making an entry. When you become better at using Thought Diary over time, you will improve your skills in dealing with negative emotions.</string>
    <string name="when_use_diary"><u>When do I use this thought diary?</u></string>
    <string name="when_use_diary_detail">Use this thought diary when you are feeling stressed, anxious, or depressed about something that happened in your life. Use this to record a situation, experience, thought, or feeling that makes you unhappy.</string>
    <string name="how_to_create_entry"><u>How to create an entry?</u></string>
    <string name="how_to_create_entry_1">1. Describe the event and identify your emotions</string>
    <string name="how_to_create_entry_2">2. Write down your negative thoughts</string>
    <string name="how_to_create_entry_3">3. Examine and challenge your negative thoughts</string>
    <string name="how_to_create_entry_4">4. Create an alternative interpretation of the situation</string>
    <string name="title">Title</string>
    <string name="how_to_write_title">Enter a short title that summarizes the situation.</string>
    <string name="emotions">Emotions</string>
    <string name="how_to_write_emotions">Choose the emotions that you felt in the situation.</string>
    <string name="distress">Distress</string>
    <string name="how_to_write_distress">Rate the level of distress you felt.</string>
    <string name="how_to_write_situation">Describe the situation in detail so that you can review and remember it later.</string>
    <string name="negative_thoughts">Negative Thoughts</string>
    <string name="how_to_write_negative_thoughts">Enter the negative thoughts you had about the situation and why it distressed you. What did you initially feel? How did you first interpret the situation?</string>
    <string name="how_to_write_cognitive_distortions">Choose some common cognitive distortions that you can find within your negative thoughts.</string>
    <string name="challenge">Challenge</string>
    <string name="how_to_write_challenge">Weigh the evidence in favor of and against your interpretation of the situation. Challenge your negative thoughts and the distortions within them.</string>
    <string name="alternative_thoughts">Alternative Thoughts</string>
    <string name="how_to_write_alternative_thoughts">Having challenged your initial negative thoughts, write an alternative interpretation or response to the situation.</string>
    <string name="emotions_ex">
        Sad\n
        Angry
    </string>
    <string name="cognitive_distortions_ex">
        Filtering out the positive\n
        Magnification of the negative\n
        Self-blaming
    </string>
    <string name="sample_diary_entry">Sample Diary Entry</string>
    <string name="title_ex">Made a mistake at work</string>
    <string name="distress_ex">8 - Severe Distress</string>
    <string name="situation_ex">I made a mistake at work today and others had to come help me fix it.</string>
    <string name="negative_thoughts_ex">I was angry at myself for making such a simple and stupid mistake. I felf helpless that I could not fix the problem by myself and useless when I had to ask others to help. I am reminded of my past failures and thinking about them makes me feel like a failure.</string>
    <string name="challenge_ex">I am being to harsh on myself. I know I make mistakes, but I am good at what I do. My coworkers appreciate my work ethic and are willing to help me fix things. Just because I am not perfect doesn\'t mean that I am a failure.</string>
    <string name="ex_distress">2 - Mild Distress</string>
    <string name="alternative_thoughts_ex">Just because I make a mistake doesn\'t mean that I am a failure at everything; my mistakes do not define me. I am successful in many ways. This event was just a learning opportunity. Dwelling on the negatives will not make me better.</string>
    <string name="acceptance_and_commitment_detail">Acceptance and Commitment Therapy uses acceptance and mindfulness strategies in conjunction with commitment and behavioral changes to increase a person\'s psychological flexibility. ACT focuses on six principles, which are detailed below.</string>
    <string name="overview">Overview</string>
    <string name="contact_with_present">Contact with present</string>
    <string name="defusion">Defusion</string>
    <string name="acceptance">Acceptance</string>
    <string name="observing_the_self">Observing the Self</string>
    <string name="values">Values</string>
    <string name="committed_action">Committed action</string>
    <string name="resource">Resource</string>
    <string name="acceptance_and_commitment">Acceptance and Commitment</string>
    <string name="act_in_nutshell"><u>ACT in a nutshell</u></string>
    <string name="act_in_nutshell_detail">ACT aims to teach you mindfulness skills to deal with painful thoughts and feelings, and to help you clarify what is truly important and valuable in your life so that you can use that knowledge to guide and motivate you to change for the better. ACT focuses on six core principles, Contact with the present moment</string>
    <string name="act_in_nutshell_detail_1">1. Defusion</string>
    <string name="act_in_nutshell_detail_2">2. Acceptance</string>
    <string name="act_in_nutshell_detail_3">3. Observing the self</string>
    <string name="act_in_nutshell_detail_4">4. Values</string>
    <string name="act_in_nutshell_detail_5">5. Committed action</string>
    <string name="act_as_therapy">ACT as therapy</string>
    <string name="act_as_therapy_detail_1">ACT can be done in one-on-one sessions, with small groups or large workshops, with books and other media, through presentations, and with behavioral homework assignments. The number and length of the sessions depend on the individual and on the clinician. ACT differs from other therapies in that it is versatile — it can be used with individuals or with groups, as long=term therapy or brief therapy, and in a wide range of clinical populations.</string>
    <string name="act_as_therapy_detail_2">In contrast to other psychotherapies, ACT\'s goal is not to reduce your symptoms. Rather, it is based on the view that trying to get rid of the \"symptoms\" in the first place is what creates a clinical disorder. Instead of trying to control the thoughts, feelings, and memories that cross your mind, ACT wants to transform the relationship you have with your negative thoughts and learn to accept and embrace them. Reducing one\'s symptoms, in this case, just happens to be a by-product (and not the goal) of the therapy.</string>
    <string name="act_as_therapy_detail_3">According to research, ACT has shown to be as effective as cognitive-behavioral therapy. It is considered an empirically validated treatment by the American Psychological Association (APA) and the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA).</string>
    <string name="act_as_therapy_detail_4">If you are interested in the learning more about ACT, the <a href='http://amzn.to/2qyBhYv'>Mindfulness and Acceptance Workbook for Depression</a> is a popular book that was written by one of the cofounders of ACT.</string>
    <string name="contact_present_1">To have contract with the present moment means to be psychologically present rather than focusing on the past or future, to be aware of the here and now, and to experience things with openness and receptiveness.</string>
    <string name="contact_present_2">There are three elements of time: past, present, and future. While reflecting on the past and planning for the future is sometimes valuable, many times problems may arise when you live more in the past or future than in the present. You may suffer as a result of continuously ruminating about the past or worrying about the future.</string>
    <string name="contact_present_3">Living life in the present means to bring your awareness to your current experience. Be aware of both your internal and external experiences and simply take note of what is happening without judging them. This may be easy to do for a few moments, but to really experience the mood-boosting effect, try to be aware for an extended period of time. It may be difficult at first, but eventually it will become easier with practice. After mastering this skill, you will be able to pull yourself to present moment whenever you find yourself unproductively ruminating about the future.</string>
    <string name="defusion_1">Cognitive defusion means to \"step back\" and observe thoughts and feelings without being caught in it; to learn to step back or detach from unhelpful thoughts, worries, or memories; to learn to let them come and go instead of getting caught up in your own thoughts. When you defuse your thoughts, they have much less influence and impact.</string>
    <string name="defusion_2">Defusion techniques should be used when there is an event or thought that is upsetting you. For example, to deal with an unpleasant thought, you might repeat that thought over and over in your head until it just becomes meaningless sound, or you might imagine it in the voice of a funny cartoon character, or sing it to the tune of a pop song, or graciously tell yourself \"Thanks, mind\" for giving you such an interesting thought.</string>
    <string name="defusion_3">Another cognitive defusion technique is this: Think about a negative and recurring self-judgment in a sentence format like \"I am X\", such as \"I am incompetent.\" Hold the thought in your mind for a couple seconds and believe in the thought as much as you can, then notice how it affects you mentally and emotionally. Next, take your thought \"I am X\" and insert the phase \"I\'m having the thought that…\" in front of it. Run through this new thought and notice now how it affects you.</string>
    <string name="defusion_4">Get creative; many tactics work as long as they help you detach yourself from the thought or get you to step back and reflect on the thought.</string>
    <string name="acceptance_1">Acceptance is allowing painful thoughts and feelings to enter your mind without struggling against them, and learn how to not be overwhelmed by them. Acceptance techniques allow you to prevent yourself from running away or avoiding the painful emotions that cross your path. The more you open up, the more these feelings can come and go without draining you or holding you back.</string>
    <string name="acceptance_2">For example, anxiety patients are taught to freely feel their anxiety without defense, and pain patients are given strategies to encourage them to let go of their struggle with pain. Reflect on whether avoiding negative thoughts, emotions, or behaviors are effective in your life, or whether struggling against the emotions are barriers that keep you from what you truly want or value. Learning to make room for these negative feelings may bring you more peace and calmness. Acceptance techniques are meant to be used as a step toward fostering value-base actions.</string>
    <string name="observing_the_self_dt_1">By observing yourself, you are training the part of your mind that is conscious of what you are thinking or feeling or doing at the moment, and you are learning to have a perspective-taking and aware sense of self.</string>
    <string name="observing_the_self_dt_2">There is a process of thinking, and then there is a process of observing that thinking. You can be aware of your own flow of thoughts and experiences without being invested in or attached to them. Learn and practice how to be observant of yourself by doing mindfulness exercises, using metaphors, and describing yourself as an \"object\" with good and bad parts. Practicing observing the self can help develop and foster other ACT principles such as defusion and acceptance.</string>
    <string name="values_dt_1">Values are important to direct and guide your life, however many people have not spent time reflecting and selecting these values. An important element of ACT is discovering what values are most important to you and identifying what you stand for and what you wish to do with your time. Finding a sense of purpose is important in aiding you on your path to recovery.</string>
    <string name="values_dt_2">Take some time to think about and analyze your values. What is important to you? What do you stand for? What principles can guide your behavior as you move through life? Keep in mind that goals and values are different. Goals are things you aspire to, while values are like a compass that directs and keeps you on track while on your life\'s journey.</string>
    <string name="committed_action_1">Committed action means setting goals that align with your values and taking actions that are guided by those values. After identifying your values, you now must work on how to live a life directed by those values. In ACT, this involves homework linked to short, medium, and long-term behavioral changes. Methods include exposure to negative thoughts or feelings, skills acquisition, and goal setting.</string>
    <string name="committed_action_2">Committed actions can start small. For example, if one of your values is building meaningful connections with people, you may start by going to lunch with a friend or colleague every day and share a piece of personal information during each lunch.</string>
    <string name="resource_link_1">
        <a href='https://www.actmindfully.com.au/upimages/Dr_Russ_Harris_-_A_Non-technical_Overview_of_ACT.pdf'>Russell Harris - Embracing Your Demons: an Overview of Accepance and Commitment Therapy (PDF)</a>
    </string>
    <string name="resource_link_2">
        <a href='https://www.goodtherapy.org/learn-about-therapy/types/acceptance-commitment-therapy'>GoodTherapy - ACT</a>
    </string>
    <string name="resource_link_3">
        <a href='https://contextualscience.org/the_six_core_processes_of_act'>The Six Core Processes of ACT</a>
    </string>


</resources>
